Go on. What was the question?
My question for you is,
so would you say your
passion now is in the
business coaching side of things?
Is that why you're doubling down on the
long form with YouTube, and is that why
you're going to go into the podcast,
build more trust, more results around
it?
What are you seeing for yourself over the
next few
years?
Okay,
so the reason I like business to business
is, one, I like talking about it.
Two, the biggest thing here is,
when I moved away from coaching, it
was 2017.
So I'm running a coaching app up until
now.
I've actually become very far removed from
my target client, my avatar.
So I'm no longer any good at personal
training because it's been so long since
I've
done it, nearly 10 years.
So almost everyone in this room
is a better coach than I
am. I still run the coaching business.
We abandoned it for a year,
and it still made money,
so we're back into it now.
It wouldn't die.
We tried to kill it.
It stayed alive.
It's like in a film where they shoot
someone in the head, and he
gets back up. We're like, "What the fuck?"
So it's been very difficult for me to
remain relatable with my perfect client
because I've been so far removed from it.
Then when I dipped a toe in the B2B
business, I was like, oh, this
is actually what
I've done. Since 2017,
I've been running a business,
and I'm pretty
much the sole marketing department of the
business.
So when you guys ask me questions,
it's not something I used to do 10 years
ago.
It's something I'm doing a lot at the
moment.
Also, the reason I enjoy this is,
one,
everything that we're going to talk about
today is dopamine related.
Like going viral, dopamine.
Getting emails, dopamine. Getting sales,
dopamine.
I'm a junkie. I fucking love it.
It wipes me out.
But then the second thing is,
when I look at the market
and the opportunity,
I would say probably at the moment I'm
doing between $2 and $3 million US a year
with this business, which is pretty good.
Right? If I can take
that YouTube from 50,000 to
300,000, I'm now thinking, okay, this
is generational wealth.
With a coaching app,
it's pretty difficult.
Adam Sullivan cracked it,
but he's the exception to the rule.
The majority of us,
for coaching businesses,
are actually creating lifestyle
businesses, and this isn't a bad thing,
by the way.
So I'm going to walk because I feel bad as
I answer this.
Actually, that feels a bit weird.
All right.
You know when you're having a three-way
with someone, and one's just sat out not
getting enough attention? Right,
I feel like that at the moment.
The what? Yeah, the cock chair,
the one just sat on it.
So this isn't to depress people for
coaching businesses.
This is briefly my story. So
2018, 2019, 2020, making good money,
not generational
wealth, not Porsche GT3 money,
but good money.
And now I'm making really good money,
but I'm kind of looking back to those
years
of just doing the coaching business,
and I miss them.
Way less stress, way less work,
way less staff.
Actually, all the way up until 2022,
it was just me.
So although I was making a quarter of the
money, I had a way better life.
So coaching businesses for us
are amazing lifestyle businesses.
You can travel, you can live,
you can pay your rent,
you can get nice things.
But it's only ever going to be a lifestyle
business.
What you don't want
is 60 staff in a coaching business.
That's why I'm so big on this brand
morphization element of it, because now
with Nutonic,
it is fucking headaches all the time.
$60,000 worth of cans,
we got the flavor wrong, and then we
had to pay two grand to get them
destroyed.
I'm like,
"We've got to pay money to throw them
away." I got a pallet of them sent
to me, by the way, down the South Coast.
They taste a little bit off,
but you still have them.
Give them for gifting.
Then this business mentorship business,
although the return on
investment, the average customer value,
all of those things are so much
more,
my quality of life has got so much worse.
I'm stressed.
I'm doing calls in the evening.
I'm doing one-to-ones with clients.
I put a 10K one-to-one package online.
I had to take it offline.
I'm still doing the calls now.
I took it offline three months ago because
I've got guys doing Ayahuasca retreats in
Brazil, I've got a
gym in the UK that I'm helping, and it
is sucking the life out of me.
So the coaching business
was a great lifestyle
business.
I kind of miss the days of it just being a
lifestyle business.
But now I've got a taste of expensive
things.
I'm in the valley of death, right?
I'm rich enough that I want to fly first
class, but I'm poor enough it still hurts.
So
I'm just trying to get out the valley of
death.
That's really what I'm trying to say here.
So the coaching businesses
are going to be your lifestyle businesses,
and you could
live a whole life on a lifestyle business.
But I'm now going through
that valley of death to the other side.
So the business mentorship thing for me
is, it's about the revenue.
It's also about the fact I enjoy it.
This day today, for me, I actually enjoy.
If I was here talking about macros
and calorie deficits, I'd probably top
myself. The other thing is, now
that I'm discovering a love for
is jujitsu.
And again jujitsu for me,
I can teach a seminar
the whole day and not get exhausted by it.
You give me a one-hour PT session,
I'll be fucked,
because I'll have to pretend I'm
enjoying it.
But it's really interesting even how you
said the maturity in your brand, because I
have a five-year-old son, Harrison,
and even seeing your
son and your transition in your life
and then business, you're
attracting a totally different avatar
and business owners outside of fitness.
And I'm just excited for you,
the way my brain is
thinking,
because I can just see the brand you've
already
built and how you can leverage off it the
more success you have with your
own business. I'm really excited for you.
I have pissed a lot of people off at the
same time, though.
Because the-
They're all going to be jealous,
so you know
... the mums from Scunthorpe
that championed me as a 26-year-old,
that might remind
them of their son, they go,
"Cunt's got a Porsche now."
But they're not the people
that I need to be fighting for.
Now, the podcast thing,
the second part of your question,
all it took was one look
at Chris Williamson's payslips,
and now I've got a podcast.
The podcast for me
was about accruing the hours.
Also,
one thing I've realized,
you know why I take the piss out of Chris,
right?
He asks questions for a living,
and people like him.
Sounds easy. I'm going to do that.
Because I
said to my manager,
"I want to go to two podcasts a week." He
goes, "I thought you
were too busy." I went, "Motherfucker,
do you understand how difficult a YouTube
video is to make?
I've got to go thumbnails,
got to go title, we've got to do the
intro, we've got to script the video,
we've got to do the setup, we've got to do
this, we've got to raise stakes,
all this."
I could just sit, press record,
and talk to someone for a fucking hour,
and
everyone's like, "Well done,
mate." I'm actually looking for the path
of least
resistance,
where I can produce an hour's content
in an hour. So actually,
my manager thinks the podcast to me
is more work.
To me, it's less work. Because
put in an hour, get an hour.
And also then you can get people to clip
it up, you
get people to do bits, whatever. To me,
that is
another investment strategy where we're
going to
get that off the ground.
And also it's just huge exposure to get ad
reads,
but the ad reads are only going to be for
Nutonic, for the TRT deal, and for the
business mentorship. Also, that means
that rather than making all these business
videos,
I could potentially just go ask cunts
questions for a while, leverage their
fame as the podcast gets bigger.
Because also, as your podcast gets bigger,
you
get access to more famous people.
More famous people gives you a wider
audience.
So that's the reason behind it. And also,
to me,
I'm a lazy marketer.
I want to find the easiest way to market
things.
I think the podcast could be that. And
if it doesn't, I'll just sell a course on
how to start a podcast.
An inception. More layers to it